<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Swift on Aleksander Zubala</title>
    <link>https://zubala.com/tags/swift/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Swift on Aleksander Zubala</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zubala.com/tags/swift/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OCMockitoSwift</title>
      <link>https://zubala.com/projects/ocmockitoswift/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubala.com/projects/ocmockitoswift/</guid>
      <description>Overview OCMockitoSwift is OCMockito adapter for Swift, that allows to create and operate on mocks which are subclasses for NSObject.
Technical details The adapter comes with two files:
 OCMockitoSwiftAdapter.{h,m} &amp;ndash; Objective-C code to provide Swift friendly interface that allows mocking, veryfing and stubbing OCMockito.swift &amp;ndash; set of global functions for Swift, e.g. mock() or verify()   Platform: iOS Framework Role: Co-Author, Developer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SzopPrecz</title>
      <link>https://zubala.com/projects/szopprecz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 15:29:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubala.com/projects/szopprecz/</guid>
      <description>Overview “SzopPrecz” (eng. Raccoon) is simple yet useful application for checking shops availability in Poland.
Starting from March 2018, shops will be closed on some Sundays (enforced by law), which leaves a burden of remembering the schedule.
Enter “SzopPrecz” — whether you’re a resident or just visiting Poland, it’s an easy way to check if shops are opened.
Features:
 check shops availability for current day schedule notification for upcoming shops close down browse through the close down schedule for 2018   Coming Soon:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swifjection</title>
      <link>https://zubala.com/projects/swifjection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 15:29:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubala.com/projects/swifjection/</guid>
      <description>Overview Swifjection &amp;ndash; lightweight and simplistic dependency injection framework written in Swift for Swift .
The main idea behind this project is to achieve DI for Swift objects that does not inherit from Objective-C classes.
Technical details We built Swifjection for our use in the first place. These are the key points what was our motivation:
 No need to inherit from NSObject in order to inject dependencies To inject pure Swift types you just need to conform to simple Injectable protocol No action required to inject NSObject sublcasses, or classes conforming to Injectable protocol Clear and simple binding system inspired by Objective-C framework Objection Lightweight &amp;ndash; we wanted to avoid unnecessary clutter and made the APIs as simple as possible   Platform: iOS Framework Role: Co-Author, Developer</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>