<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aleksander Zubala</title>
    <link>http://zubala.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Aleksander Zubala</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 14:37:18 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://zubala.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://zubala.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 14:37:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zubala.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a software developer from Warsaw, Poland. I have graduated from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elka.pw.edu.pl/eng&#34;&gt;Warsaw University of Technology at the Faculty of Electronics and Information Technology&lt;/a&gt;. I have solid background in digital signal processing and advanced video coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software was my hobby from an early age, my first code was on Amstrad in &lt;code&gt;QBASIC&lt;/code&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about Apple products and my favourite programming languages are: &lt;code&gt;Swift&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Objective-C&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;C&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Python&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 2010 I professionally develop iOS applications, my first commercial project was Polityka - the polish weekly magazine on iPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2013 I came back to Poland after year and a half in Berlin where I worked at &lt;strong&gt;Neofonie Mobile GmbH&lt;/strong&gt;. During that period I was a lead developer of the Bild on iPad and an app for the Berliner Philharmoniker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After return to Warsaw I&amp;rsquo;ve joined &lt;strong&gt;Taptera Poland&lt;/strong&gt;, were I took part in some interesting enterprise projects for US clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently I&amp;rsquo;m working at &lt;strong&gt;Applause Inc.&lt;/strong&gt;, where I&amp;rsquo;m responsible for  iOS team. As a part time job I&amp;rsquo;m also a co-founder of &lt;strong&gt;Mobile Academy&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; organization for mobile workshops. I&amp;rsquo;m also a consultant in &lt;strong&gt;Sependa&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; mainly helping with their flag product called Crescendo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my spare time I do a little bit of swimming and cycling (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/athletes/9515088&#34;&gt;follow me on Strava&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Parts Company</title>
      <link>http://zubala.com/projects/electronic-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 15:50:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zubala.com/projects/electronic-parts/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An iPad application for sales representatives of the company which produces electronic parts. The key idea was to create diagram of future product of the customer and identify parts which the company could sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application was integrated with Salesforce, this way when sales rep created diagram, he could directly from the app create leads and opportunities on Salesforce platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technical-details&#34;&gt;Technical details&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was responsible for the component for designing and rendering diagrams on the iPad. Solution was based on the Apple&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;UICollectionView&lt;/code&gt; and custom layout. The most challenging part was to optimize performance of the diagram. It could contain multiple items connected to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>App for Insurance Company</title>
      <link>http://zubala.com/projects/insurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 15:52:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zubala.com/projects/insurance/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile application that allows user to file an insurance claim and track its status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Claim reports were persistent and could be continued at any time. User could also evaluate his car and request contact with company&amp;rsquo;s agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technical-details&#34;&gt;Technical details&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application communicated with the backend service with &lt;strong&gt;SOAP&lt;/strong&gt; technology. Forms were based on the custom built framework based on the &lt;code&gt;UITableView&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Academy</title>
      <link>http://zubala.com/projects/mobile-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 15:54:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zubala.com/projects/mobile-academy/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Co-founder of &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobile-academy.io&#34;&gt;Mobile Academy&lt;/a&gt; organistation which orgnise workshops for the iOS community around Poland and Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far we&amp;rsquo;ve visted cities like: Warszawa, Kraków, Gdańsk, Łódz in Poland. We&amp;rsquo;ve also been in Berlin and Minsk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technical-details&#34;&gt;Technical details&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve conducted the following workshops:
- Introduction to TDD on iOS
- Workshop about &lt;code&gt;UICollectionView&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we are constantly working on new ones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bild.de iPad Application</title>
      <link>http://zubala.com/projects/bild/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 15:29:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zubala.com/projects/bild/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second edition of the app for the Germany&amp;rsquo;s biggest newspaper. The concept of the app is based on the current web page - app meant to be fast, reliable and fun to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bild is all about the content; app is full of visuals, which has to be handle efficiently on all available iPad versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Available in AppStore on May 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technical-details&#34;&gt;Technical details&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Custom &lt;code&gt;UICollectionView&lt;/code&gt;-like mechanisms to implement dynamic feeds display (support for iOS 5.x prevents from using original components), feed caching mechanisms, Single Sign On/One Click Buy&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Szymanowski iPad Application</title>
      <link>http://zubala.com/projects/szymanowski/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 15:57:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zubala.com/projects/szymanowski/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Showcase app about the famous polish composer. The app is full of the audio/video content and articles about the artist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Available on the AppStore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technical-details&#34;&gt;Technical details&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Custom framework based on Apple&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;CoreText&lt;/code&gt; for rendering rich text with style and hyper links (before &lt;code&gt;TextKit&lt;/code&gt; was available).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Concert Hall</title>
      <link>http://zubala.com/projects/dch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 15:47:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zubala.com/projects/dch/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First version of the universal app for the world’s best philharmonic – Berliner Phil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User can preview the past concerts and its pieces, but the most important feature is that one can experience the live concert straight from the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clean design, presents the content without any distraction. Available on the AppStore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technical-details&#34;&gt;Technical details&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Efficient horizontal scroll view based on &lt;code&gt;UIScrollView&lt;/code&gt;, to handle hundreds of archive concerts. HTTP Live streaming and integreation with Apple&amp;rsquo;s In-App purchase framework &lt;code&gt;StoreKit&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AAC&#43; Player</title>
      <link>http://zubala.com/projects/aac_player/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 15:29:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zubala.com/projects/aac_player/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fully featured player for audio streams encoded with AAC+. Framework provide mechanism for bufferning the stream and playback control. Library packaged in the way the systems frameworks are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technical-details&#34;&gt;Technical details&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inegrated Custom AAC+ decoder written in C, which delivered raw encoded audio samples, the iOS library was responsible for feeding raw data into cyclic &lt;code&gt;CoreAudio&lt;/code&gt; buffers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polityka on iPad</title>
      <link>http://zubala.com/projects/polityka/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 15:56:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zubala.com/projects/polityka/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iPad’s edition of the polish weekly magazine, based on the [Pixblish]() framework.
Newsstand app for the fully native app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, the app was the first polish app which used auto – renewable subscription for the subscription.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technical-details&#34;&gt;Technical details&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the first was built with Pixblish framework developed at Polidea. We built a solution to render rich text with media on iPad based on &lt;code&gt;XML&lt;/code&gt; description. The weekly issue was composed on our back-end which generated packaged, then rendered on iOS Device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integration of Apple&amp;rsquo;s framework for Newsstand and In-App Purchase. The main challenge was to test auto-renewable subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>