<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>project on Aleksander Zubala</title>
    <link>https://zubala.com/categories/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in project on Aleksander Zubala</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zubala.com/categories/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OCMockitoSwift</title>
      <link>https://zubala.com/projects/ocmockitoswift/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubala.com/projects/ocmockitoswift/</guid>
      <description>Overview OCMockitoSwift is OCMockito adapter for Swift, that allows to create and operate on mocks which are subclasses for NSObject.
Technical details The adapter comes with two files:
 OCMockitoSwiftAdapter.{h,m} &amp;ndash; Objective-C code to provide Swift friendly interface that allows mocking, veryfing and stubbing OCMockito.swift &amp;ndash; set of global functions for Swift, e.g. mock() or verify()   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SzopPrecz</title>
      <link>https://zubala.com/projects/szopprecz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 15:29:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubala.com/projects/szopprecz/</guid>
      <description>Overview “SzopPrecz” (eng. Raccoon) is simple yet useful application for checking shops availability in Poland.
Starting from March 2018, shops will be closed on some Sundays (enforced by law), which leaves a burden of remembering the schedule.
Enter “SzopPrecz” — whether you’re a resident or just visiting Poland, it’s an easy way to check if shops are opened.
Features:
 check shops availability for current day schedule notification for upcoming shops close down browse through the close down schedule for 2018  Coming Soon:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swifjection</title>
      <link>https://zubala.com/projects/swifjection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 15:29:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubala.com/projects/swifjection/</guid>
      <description>Overview Swifjection &amp;ndash; lightweight and simplistic dependency injection framework written in Swift for Swift .
The main idea behind this project is to achieve DI for Swift objects that does not inherit from Objective-C classes.
Technical details We built Swifjection for our use in the first place. These are the key points what was our motivation:
 No need to inherit from NSObject in order to inject dependencies To inject pure Swift types you just need to conform to simple Injectable protocol No action required to inject NSObject sublcasses, or classes conforming to Injectable protocol Clear and simple binding system inspired by Objective-C framework Objection Lightweight &amp;ndash; we wanted to avoid unnecessary clutter and made the APIs as simple as possible   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applause iOS SDK</title>
      <link>https://zubala.com/projects/applause/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 19:36:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubala.com/projects/applause/</guid>
      <description>Overview Applause iOS SDK is a framework for Mobie Beta Management service. It&amp;rsquo;s a library that customer integrates with his application in order to receive users feedback and bug reports about his product. In addition Beta Management also includes participant session information as well as automatic crash reporting. To make sense of all the incoming data, the dashboard filters and neatly organizes bugs, feedback, session logs and crash reports in real time to maximize your efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Parts Company</title>
      <link>https://zubala.com/projects/electronic-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 15:50:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubala.com/projects/electronic-parts/</guid>
      <description>Overview An iPad application for sales representatives of the company which produces electronic parts. The key idea was to create diagram of future product of the customer and identify parts which the company could sell.
Application was integrated with Salesforce, this way when sales rep created diagram, he could directly from the app create leads and opportunities on Salesforce platform.
Technical details I was responsible for the component for designing and rendering diagrams on the iPad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>App for Insurance Company</title>
      <link>https://zubala.com/projects/insurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 15:52:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubala.com/projects/insurance/</guid>
      <description>Overview Mobile application that allows user to file an insurance claim and track its status.
Claim reports were persistent and could be continued at any time. User could also evaluate his car and request contact with company&amp;rsquo;s agent.
Technical details Application communicated with the backend service with SOAP technology. Forms were based on the custom built framework based on the UITableView.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Academy</title>
      <link>https://zubala.com/projects/mobile-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 15:54:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubala.com/projects/mobile-academy/</guid>
      <description>Overview Co-founder of Mobile Academy organistation which orgnise workshops for the iOS community around Poland and Europe.
So far we&amp;rsquo;ve visted cities like: Warszawa, Kraków, Gdańsk, Łódz in Poland. We&amp;rsquo;ve also been in Berlin and Minsk.
Technical details We&amp;rsquo;ve conducted the following workshops:
 Introduction to TDD on iOS Workshop about UICollectionView  And we are constantly working on new ones.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bild.de iPad Application</title>
      <link>https://zubala.com/projects/bild/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 15:29:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubala.com/projects/bild/</guid>
      <description>Overview The second edition of the app for the Germany&amp;rsquo;s biggest newspaper. The concept of the app is based on the current web page - app meant to be fast, reliable and fun to use.
Bild is all about the content; app is full of visuals, which has to be handle efficiently on all available iPad versions.
Available in AppStore on May 2013.
Technical details Custom UICollectionView-like mechanisms to implement dynamic feeds display (support for iOS 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Szymanowski iPad Application</title>
      <link>https://zubala.com/projects/szymanowski/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 15:57:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubala.com/projects/szymanowski/</guid>
      <description>Overview Showcase app about the famous polish composer. The app is full of the audio/video content and articles about the artist.
Available on the AppStore.
Technical details Custom framework based on Apple&amp;rsquo;s CoreText for rendering rich text with style and hyper links (before TextKit was available).
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Concert Hall</title>
      <link>https://zubala.com/projects/dch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 15:47:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubala.com/projects/dch/</guid>
      <description>Overview First version of the universal app for the world’s best philharmonic – Berliner Phil.
User can preview the past concerts and its pieces, but the most important feature is that one can experience the live concert straight from the app.
Clean design, presents the content without any distraction. Available on the AppStore.
Technical details Efficient horizontal scroll view based on UIScrollView, to handle hundreds of archive concerts. HTTP Live streaming and integreation with Apple&amp;rsquo;s In-App purchase framework StoreKit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AAC&#43; Player</title>
      <link>https://zubala.com/projects/aac_player/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 15:29:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubala.com/projects/aac_player/</guid>
      <description>Overview Fully featured player for audio streams encoded with AAC+. Framework provide mechanism for buffering the stream and playback control. Library packaged in the way the systems frameworks are.
Technical details Integrated Custom AAC+ decoder written in C, which delivered raw encoded audio samples, the iOS library was responsible for feeding raw data into cyclic CoreAudio buffers.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polityka on iPad</title>
      <link>https://zubala.com/projects/polityka/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 15:56:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubala.com/projects/polityka/</guid>
      <description>Overview iPad’s edition of the polish weekly magazine, based on the Pixblish framework. Newsstand app for the fully native app.
At the time, the app was the first polish app which used auto – renewable subscription for the subscription.
Technical details This was the first was built with Pixblish framework developed at Polidea. We built a solution to render rich text with media on iPad based on XML description. The weekly issue was composed on our back-end which generated packaged, then rendered on iOS Device.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
