<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Freelance on Aleksander Zubala</title>
    <link>https://zubala.com/tags/freelance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Freelance on Aleksander Zubala</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 15:52:28 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zubala.com/tags/freelance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>App for Insurance Company</title>
      <link>https://zubala.com/projects/insurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 15:52:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubala.com/projects/insurance/</guid>
      <description>Overview Mobile application that allows user to file an insurance claim and track its status.
Claim reports were persistent and could be continued at any time. User could also evaluate his car and request contact with company&amp;rsquo;s agent.
Technical details Application communicated with the backend service with SOAP technology. Forms were based on the custom built framework based on the UITableView.
 Client: Polish Insurance Company Platform: iOS Universal Application Role: Team member</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Academy</title>
      <link>https://zubala.com/projects/mobile-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 15:54:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubala.com/projects/mobile-academy/</guid>
      <description>Overview Co-founder of Mobile Academy organistation which orgnise workshops for the iOS community around Poland and Europe.
So far we&amp;rsquo;ve visted cities like: Warszawa, Kraków, Gdańsk, Łódz in Poland. We&amp;rsquo;ve also been in Berlin and Minsk.
Technical details We&amp;rsquo;ve conducted the following workshops: - Introduction to TDD on iOS - Workshop about UICollectionView
And we are constantly working on new ones.
 Client: Mobile Academy Platform: iOS Role: Tutor</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Szymanowski iPad Application</title>
      <link>https://zubala.com/projects/szymanowski/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 15:57:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubala.com/projects/szymanowski/</guid>
      <description>Overview Showcase app about the famous polish composer. The app is full of the audio/video content and articles about the artist.
Available on the AppStore.
Technical details Custom framework based on Apple&amp;rsquo;s CoreText for rendering rich text with style and hyper links (before TextKit was available).
 Client: Szymanowski  Platform: iPad Application  Role: Developer, Design</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AAC&#43; Player</title>
      <link>https://zubala.com/projects/aac_player/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 15:29:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubala.com/projects/aac_player/</guid>
      <description>Overview Fully featured player for audio streams encoded with AAC+. Framework provide mechanism for buffering the stream and playback control. Library packaged in the way the systems frameworks are.
Technical details Integrated Custom AAC+ decoder written in C, which delivered raw encoded audio samples, the iOS library was responsible for feeding raw data into cyclic CoreAudio buffers.
 Client: AAC+ Player Platform: iOS Framework Role: Developer, Solution Architect</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>